[
    {
        "question": "Under which minister’s tenure Banking was a private sector.",
        "options": [
            "Indira Gandhi and Nehru",
            "Nehru and Shastri",
            "Shastri and Indira",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city was the first textile Mill started in India.",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Delhi",
            "Madras"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Mention the time frame when India was facing with famine during the planning phase.",
        "options": [
            "1956-59",
            "1951-56",
            "1966-69"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year did India mortgaged or sold some of its Gold reserves for controlling the deficit situation ofIndia?",
        "options": [
            "May 1991",
            "May 1992"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct full form of IRDP:",
        "options": [
            "Integrated Rural Development Programme",
            "Indian Rural Development Plan"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In which plan did population control was as an objective.",
        "options": [
            "Sixth Five year Plan, 1980-85",
            "First Five year plan, 1951-56",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Scarcity of capital, technological backwardness and unemployment are generally found in",
        "options": [
            "Developed countries",
            "Underdeveloped countries",
            "Both 1 & 2",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which plan was Pradhanmantri Rozgar Yojana initiated.",
        "options": [
            "Second Five year Plan",
            "Sixth Five year plan",
            "Fourth Five year plan",
            "Eight Five year plan"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Which plan brought-forth balance in industries and Agriculture.",
        "options": [
            "Third Five year plan (1961-66)",
            "First Five year plan (1951-56)"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "How many banks were Nationalized on 19 July,1969.",
        "options": [
            "14",
            "16",
            "12",
            "10"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the man who established the Planning Commission in India, 1950.",
        "options": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Pandit Jawahar Lal Nehru",
            "Subhash Chandra Pose"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year did government start a rolling plan?",
        "options": [
            "April 1978",
            "April 1979",
            "April 1988",
            "April 1956"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In a capitalist economy,",
        "options": [
            "The means of production are privately owned",
            "The means of production are owned by the state",
            "The means are owned by both the state and private individuals."
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct period of First Five year Plan:",
        "options": [
            "1951-56",
            "1950-55",
            "1949-54"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following explains the term economic development?",
        "options": [
            "Improvement in the technology involved",
            "Improvement in production",
            "Improvement in distribution system",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year was Imperial Bank converted into State Bank of India.",
        "options": [
            "1955",
            "1956"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "India falls under the following economy:",
        "options": [
            "Capitalist",
            "Socialist",
            "Mixed",
            "Mixed"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following explains the term economic growth?",
        "options": [
            "Increase in per capita production",
            "Increase in per capita real income",
            "Structural change in the economy",
            "All the above"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Five year plan period did Government suffer due to pay raise of Government and Railway servants?",
        "options": [
            "1951-56, First Five year plan",
            "1969-74, Fourth Five year plan"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Economic development is characterized by",
        "options": [
            "Structural change in the economy",
            "Change in the occupational structure",
            "Both 1 and 2",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the First Bank of India.",
        "options": [
            "Awas Yojana",
            "Imperial Bank"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Capital formation in underdeveloped countries is a major bottleneck. The reason can be",
        "options": [
            "Small size of market with no incentive for investment",
            "Low level of income",
            "Demonstration effect",
            "All the above"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year was the Free market policy adopted in India?",
        "options": [
            "1993",
            "1992",
            "1991",
            "1990"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Five year plan, did the scheme of 10 lakh wells was brought-forth.",
        "options": [
            "First Five year Plan",
            "Third Five year plan",
            "Seventh Five year plan"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    }
]